Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の代価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本　等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
To obtain more information about
the transmutation of living organisms,
生体錬成の知識を得るため
Ed and Al visited Shou Tucker, the Sewing-Life Alchemist.
綴命の錬金術師ショウ·タッカーの家を訪ねたエドとアル
At his house, they met his daughter, Nina, and their dog, Alexander.
そこには娘のニーナと犬のアレキサンダーがいた
In order to pass the assessment for State Alchemists,
Tucker transmuted a chimera using Nina and Alexander.
タッカーは国家錬金術師の査定を通るため
ニーナとアレキサンダーを使って　合成獣を錬成した
Nina will never be able to return to her old self.
ニーナは二度と元に戻らない
Ed was grief-stricken by his powerlessness.
エドは己の無力さに打ちひしがれるのであった
Mom! Mom!
母さん　お母さん
What's the matter, Ed?
どうしたの　エド
A present for you.
プレゼント
I transmuted it myself!
僕が錬成したんだよ
Is that so?
エドが　さすが父さんの子ね
You're Daddy's son, all right.
Thank you.
ありがとう　本当にエドはすごいわ
You're really amazing, Ed.
To be able to make something wonderful like this.
こんなに立派なものを作れるなんて
But...
でも
You... couldn't make me correctly, could you...
お母さんは　ちゃんと創ってくれなかったのね
Onii-chan.
おにいちゃん
Let's play.
遊ぼ
Are you all right, Brother?
大丈夫　兄さん
Seemed like you were having a nightmare.
魘されてたよ
What's the matter, you two? Isn't it
a bit early in the morning to be here?
どうしたの二人とも
こんな朝早くから
Umm...
あ　あのさ
So what's going to happen to Tucker and Nina?
タッカーとニーナ　どうなるの
Mr. Tucker was supposed to be put on trial
and have his State Alchemist qualifications stripped...
タッカー氏は資格剥奪のうえ
裁判にかけられる予定だったけど
...but both of them died.
死んだわ　二人とも
"Died"?
死んだ
I'll go ahead and let you know now, since you'll find out sooner or later.
いずれ分かることだから教えておくわね
They were killed.
殺されたのよ
Why?!
なんで
誰に
By who?!
分からないわ
We don't know.
I'm about to head to the scene myself.
私もこれから現場へ行くところなの
We're coming with you.
僕たちも行きます
ダメよ
I can't allow you to.
Why not?!
どうして
You're better off not seeing it.
見ない方がいい
Looks like we were a bit late.
ひと足遅かったか
We'll have to go after him soon. Or else...
早く追いつかねば　このままでは
You sound as if you knew this was going to happen.
事件を予期していたような口ぶりだな
What's this about?
どういうわけだ
God has given us a trial!
神は試練を与えたもうた
Evil heathens are trying to disturb our faith by spreading absurd rumors, and the military is planning to oppress us!
邪悪なる異教徒があらぬ噂を広めて
我らの信仰心を乱し
軍は弾圧を企んでいる
But we shall not give in!
だが屈してはならん
Take up arms and rise!
今こそ武器を手に立ち上がるのだ
In the name of our almighty Sun God, Leto!
偉大なるレト神の名の下に
That's right! We've got the Sun God Leto on our side!
そうだ　オレたちにはレト神がついている
Shoot the heathens!
異教徒を打ち倒せ
Hey! Don't let him trick you!
おい　だまされるな
That bastard has been lying to us!
そいつは　オレたちにウソをついてたんだぞ
Shut up!
黙れ
You guys are agents of the heathens, aren't you!
お前ら　異教徒の手先だな
Humans are oh so silly.
人間ってどうしようもなく愚かだわ
Don't you agree, Gluttony?
そう思わない　グラトニー
Foolish! Foolish!
愚か愚か
Yeah, seriously.
ああ　まったくだ
Oh my, Sir High Priest.
これはこれは教主様
Sir!
様ぁ
Sorry for giving you so much trouble.
悪いわね　手を煩わせちゃって
I'll be returning to my assigned town once all of this is over.
これが終わったら
さっさと受け持ちの街に帰らせてもらうさ
The fullmetal boy got in our way, but we were able to make good use of him in the end.
鋼の坊やには邪魔されたけど
結局うまく利用できたわ
Looks like this'll be over quicker than we'd expected.
予定より早く終わりそうね
All of this happened just because you manipulated a bit of information and I stirred the believers.
あんたがちょっと情報操作して
わしが信者どもを煽ってやっただけでこの有様だ
Humans are such simple beings.
単純だよ　人間ってやつは
Blood calls for blood, while hatred begets hatred,
流血は流血を　憎悪は憎悪を呼び
and the energy that comes forth begins to take root in this earth and engraves a crest of blood.
膨れ上がったエネルギーは
この地に根を下ろし血の紋を刻む
They never learn, no matter how many times history is repeated.
何度繰り返しても学ぶことを知らない
Humans are foolish, sorrowful creatures.
人間は愚かで悲しい生き物だわ
But that's why we can have them play right into our hands, is it not?
だから我々の思うツボなんだろ
Will more people die?
またいっぱい人が死ぬ
Yes, they will.
ええ　死ぬわ
Can I eat all the ones that died?
死んだの全部食べていい
No eating.
食べちゃダメ
In any case Envy, just how much longer do you plan to stay in that form?
ところでエンヴィー
いつまでその格好してるつもり
It's kind of gross.
気持ち悪いわよ
Oh come on, I'm just going with the flow.
やだな　ノリだよノリ
But I guess it's better to transform into someone young and cute, huh?
でもどうせ変身するなら
やっぱり若くてかわいい方がいいよね
M-Monster!!!
ばっ 化け物
What's this?!
どういうことだ
The High Priest...
教主は　本物のコーネロ教主どこに行った
What happened to the real High Priest?!
What do we do?
どうする
He called me a monster. How rude.
化け物だってさ　失礼しちゃうよね
Can I eat him?
食べていい
Oh yeah, I heard Shou Tucker from East City was killed.
そういえばさぁ
イーストシティのショウ·タッカーが殺されたって
Tucker?
タッカー
Ah well, who cares about small fry like him?
ああ　いいんじゃないの　あんな雑魚
Well, the guy who killed him is none other than that guy.
それが殺したの例のヤツなんだよね
If we're talking about East City, isn't the Flame Colonel stationed there?
イーストシティっていったら
焔の大佐がいたかしら
Yup. The fullmetal brat is there, too, it seems.
そう　鋼のおチビさんも滞在中らしいよ
Fullmetal...
鋼の
It makes me mad that he interfered with our work, but we can't let him die.
仕事の邪魔してくれたのは腹が立つけど
死なせるわけにはいかないわね
He's an important human sacrifice, after all.
大事な人柱だし
Thanks for the meal!
ごちそうさま
Got it. We'll take care of it somehow.
分かったわ　それはこっちでなんとかする
So, what's that guy's name again?
で　なんて言ったっけ　例のヤツ
Scar?
スカー　傷の男
Scarred man...
Yeah. We don't know anything about him,
so that's what we call him.
ああ　素性が分からんから
オレたちはそう呼んでる
We have no idea what his aim is, and he's extremely elusive.
目的も不明にして神出鬼没
All we know about him is that
he has a large scar on his forehead.
額に大きな傷があるということぐらいしか
情報がないのです
I've heard rumors about him, but...
噂は耳にしていたが
So that's who you guys have been after.
そいつを追ってきたわけか
It was on the recommendations from military police headquarters.
憲兵司令部のお声がかりでな
I've got so much work from the chamber of military, too.
軍法会議所の仕事も山積みだってのに　頭痛ぇよ
Seriously, all this is giving me a headache...
We've got five casualties so far in Central, ten nationwide. All State Alchemists.
国家錬金術師ばかり
中央で５人
国内ですと　１０人が被害に遭っております
Old man Gran was killed five days ago, too.
５日前にはグランのじいさんも殺られてる
Brigadier General Gran?!
グラン准将が
He was the lead of weapons transmutation and troop combat divisions!
兵器錬成と軍隊格闘の第一人者だぞ
That's how much trouble this guy really is.
それくらいやばいヤツだってことさ
Listen to me. Deploy more guards and stay put for a while.
悪いことは言わん　護衛を増やして
しばらく大人しくしててくれ
I'm asking this as a friend, too.
これは親友としての頼みでもある
The only famous alchemists around here were you and Tucker, right?
ここらで有名どころといったら
タッカーとお前さんだけだろ
Shit!
あっ　まずい
I've always been thinking.
What is this alchemy we believe in?
オレたちの信じる錬金術ってなんだろうって
ずっと考えてた
"Alchemy is understanding the various rules and flow that exist within matter, breaking it down, then rebuilding it."
錬金術とは物質の内に存在する法則と流れを知り
分解し　再構築すること
"This world also flows while abiding by those rules and is in a cycle."
この世界も法則に従って流れ　循環している
"Death is also a part of that flow. Accept the flow entirely."
人が死ぬのもその流れのうち
流れを受け入れろ
って　先生によく言われたっけ
That's what our master always said, isn't it?
I thought I understood.
分かってるつもりだった
But I didn't.
でも分かってなかった
That's why we transmuted Mom...
だから母さんを
And even now, I'm thinking whether I could somehow fix something that's impossible.
そして今もどうにもならないことを
どうにかできないかと考えてる
I'm an idiot.
オレはバカだ
I haven't grown one bit since that time.
あのときから少しも成長しちゃいない
I thought that rain would wash away these pent-up feelings...
雨ならもやもやした気持ち
流してくれると思ったけど
But every drop that hits my face makes me more miserable.
今は顔に当たるひと粒すら鬱陶しい
I can't even feel the rain hitting my skin because I have no body.
肉体を持たない僕には　雨が肌を打つ感覚もない
That by itself is lonely and cruel.
それは寂しいしつらい
I still want to return to my old body. I want to become human again.
僕はやっぱり元の体に　人間に戻りたい
Even if it's impossible and is against the ways of this world.
それが世の流れに逆らう
どうにもならないことだとしても
You're Edward Elric, the "Fullmetal Alchemist", aren't you?
鋼の錬金術師エドワード·エルリックだな
Brother!
兄さん
What the hell is this about?!
何なんだ　一体
Who the hell is this guy?
なんだこいつ
This is bad... This is bad!
やばい　やばい
I've got to get away!
逃げなきゃ
This is bad... This is bad!
やばい　やばい
Al, run!
アル　逃げろ
I won't let you get away!
逃がさん
Brother!
兄さん
Al, hang on!
アル つかまれ
Dammit, what the hell?!
ちくしょ　なんだってんだ
I haven't done anything to set anyone against me-
人に恨みを買うようなことは
Scratch that, I've done a lot.
いっぱいしてるけど
I haven't given anyone reason to go after my life, though!
命狙われる筋合いはねぇぞ
Oww...
痛ぇ
Who the hell are you? Why are you after us?!
あんた何者だ　なんでオレたちを狙う
Think of it this way:
貴様ら創る者がいれば
If there is someone who created you,
then there is someone who will destroy you, as well.
壊す者もいるということだ
Looks like there's no getting out of this.
やるしかねぇってか
You've got some guts.
いい度胸だ
But...
だが
Too slow.
遅い
Al!
アル
中身がない
It's empty?
You bastard!!!
野郎
遅い
Too slow!
Dammit!
くそっ
Automail...
機械鎧
なるほど　人体破壊では壊せぬはずだ
Makes sense. I wouldn't be able to
destroy it with human destruction.
変わったヤツらよ
You guys are something else.
兄さん　ダメだ
No, Brother!
逃げた方が
You should run!
バカ野郎　お前を置いて逃げられっか
Idiot! How can I leave you behind and run?!
両手を合わせて輪を作り　錬成を行うわけか
So you transmute by placing your hands together and forming a circle.
ならば
In that case...
おらぁ
まずは　この鬱陶しい右腕を破壊させてもらう
I'll be destroying this annoying arm of yours, first.
兄さん
Brother!!!
これでもう錬金術は使えない
Now you can't use alchemy anymore.
神に祈る間をやろう
I'll give you a bit of time to pray to God.
Brother, run! Brother!
兄さん　逃げて
兄さん
Unfortunately, there isn't a god I want to pray to.
あいにくだけど　祈りたい神様がいないんでね
あんたが狙ってるのはオレだけか
Am I the only one you're after?
弟　アルも殺す気か
Are you going to kill my brother... Al... too?
邪魔をするならば排除する
I will, if he decides to interfere.
But the only one to receive judgment
at my hands is the Fullmetal Alchemist... You...
だが　裁きを下すのは鋼の錬金術師　貴様だけだ
All right...
そうか
じゃあ約束しろ
Then promise me.
弟には手を出さないと
That you won't lay a finger on my little brother!
はっ　兄さん
Brother...
I'll keep my word.
約束は守ろう
何言ってんだよ　兄さん
What are you saying... Brother?
何してる　逃げろよ
What are you doing? Get out of there?!
立って逃げるんだよ
Get up and run!
やめろ　やめろ
Stop it... Stop it.
Stop it! You bastard!!!
やめろ　貴様
そこまでだ
That's far enough.
You've made quite a mess of things, Scar.
随分と派手に暴れてくれたな　スカー
一連の国家錬金術師殺しの犯人として
I'll be taking you into custody under the offense of murdering a series of State Alchemists.
貴様の身柄を拘束する
Alchemists are beings who alter the original form of matter.
錬金術師とは元来あるべき姿を異形へと変える者
それ即ち　万物の創造主たる神への冒涜
In other words, an affront to God, the creator of all.
我は神の代行者として裁きを下す者なり
I bring judgment, acting as God's hand.
邪魔をするならば貴様も排除する
If you choose to get in my way, I will eliminate you, as well.
おもしろい
Interesting.
お前たちは手を出すな
I don't want any of you interfering in this.
マスタング大佐
Colonel Mustang!
マスタング　焔の錬金術師
Mustang... The Flame Alchemist.
自ら裁きを受けに出向いてくるとは
You came to me to receive judgment,
saving me the effort of having to search for you.
今日はなんとよき日よ
What a splendid day!
我が名を知ってなお戦いを挑むか
You know my name, yet you're picking a fight with me?
What a fool.
愚か者め
いきなり何をするんだ　君は
What was that for?!
大佐は下がっててください
Colonel, please stay back.
雨の日は無能なんですから
You're impotent on rainy days, after all.
Oh right, I guess you can't make sparks when it's wet like this.
ああそうか　こう湿ってちゃ火花出せないよな
It's awfully convenient for me if you can't make flames, State Alchemist.
炎を出せぬとは好都合だ
国家錬金術師
我が使命を邪魔する者　この場の全員を滅ぼす
I will destroy all here who interfere with my duty!
やってみるがよい
We'll just see about that!
新手か
Reinforcements?!
我が輩の一撃をかわすとは
You're quite good to be able to dodge my fist.
やりおる　やりおる
全員を滅ぼすと言ったな
You said you'd destroy everyone here, no?
ならばまず　この我が輩を倒してみせよ
Then try defeating me, first!
豪腕の錬金術師　アレックス·ルイ·アームストロングを
The Strong Arm Alchemist, Alex Louis Armstrong!!!
次から次へと
One after another...
これも神の導きか
This must be divine guidance, as well.
So you won't retreat, huh?
退かぬか
その勇気に敬意を表して見せてやろう
To show deference to that courage, I'll show you...
我がアームストロング家に代々伝わりし芸術的錬金法を
...a skill that has been passed down the Armstrong household for generations... Artistic Alchemy!
ヤツは
Who is he?
タッカー氏を殺害した犯人だ
He's the one who murdered Mr. Tucker.
ヤツが
It was him ?!
つか少佐　あんまり街を破壊せんでください
Major! Please try not to destroy too much of the city!
何を言う
What are you saying?!
Destruction and creation are like two sides of the same coin!
破壊と創造は表裏一体
壊して創る　これ即ち大宇宙の法則なり
You destroy and create! This, in other words,
is the law of the universe!
なぜ裸
But why naked...
無茶苦茶な理屈だな
That logic is crazy...
同じ錬金術師ならむちゃとは思わんさ
But other Alchemists won't find it crazy, though.
そうだろう　スカーよ
Right, Scar?
ヤツも錬金術師か
So he's an Alchemist, too...
I see. The three transmutation processes in Alchemy are understanding, decomposition, and reconstruction.
そうか
錬金術の錬成過程は　理解分解再構築の三つ
あいつはそれを分解で止めてるんだ
But he stops at the point of decomposition.
自分も錬金術師って
He's an alchemist, too?
それじゃああいつ自身が
Then he is going against "God's path", isn't he?!
神の道ってやつに背いてるじゃないか
But... why is he only after those who possess a state qualification?
しかも　なぜ国家資格を持つ者ばかを狙うのか
体に似合わぬ身のこなしと
Agility that wouldn't be expected from
his build and inhuman destructive power.
常人離れした破壊力
そして錬金術
And on top of that, alchemy...
厄介ではあるが
He's certainly troublesome, but...
Now you're stuck!
追い詰めたり
...this is when he takes a big swing!
ここぞというところで大振りになる
Right here!
ここだ
He pulled back?!
はっ 間合いを
やったか
Did you get him?!
He's fast.
速いですね
１発かすっただけです
Just one hit, a graze.
褐色の肌に　赤い目
Brown skin and red eyes?!
イシュヴァールの民か
An Ishbalan?!
囲まれたか
Looks like I'm surrounded...
おっと動くなよ　この包囲から
Hey now, don't move-
野郎　地下水道に
Damn, the bastard escaped into the sewers...
追うなよ
Don't go after him.
追いませんよ　あんな危ないヤツ
Like I'd go after a dangerous guy like that.
すまんな
Sorry about that.
包囲するだけの時間を稼いでもらったというのに
You bought enough time for us to surround him, and yet...
いえ　時間稼ぎどころか
No, I was more concerned with
staying alive rather than buying time.
殺られぬようにするのが精一杯で
おっ　終わったか
Oh, is it over?
ヒューズ中佐　今までどこに
Lt. Colonel Hughes, where have you been?
物陰に隠れてた
I was taking cover.
お前なぁ　援護とかしろよ
Hey! Why didn't you at least give support or something?!
うるせぇ
Shut up! Don't drag an ordinary guy like me
into you nonsensical mutants' all-around freak shows!
オレみたいな一般人を
お前らでたらめ人間の万国ビックリショーに
巻き込むんじゃねぇ
What are you gazing off into space for?! Don't you guys have work to do?!
ぼっとしてねぇで　やることあるだろ
市内緊急配備　人相書きまわせよ
Emergency deployments within the city! And be sure to whip up a description about the suspect, too!
はっ
Yes, sir!
アルフォンス
Alphonse...
Alphonse!
アル　大丈夫か　おい
Al! Are you all right?! Hey!
あれが　エルリックの弟とは
So that's Elric's younger brother...
深い事情がありそっすね
Looks like they've got their own issues...
Al! Alphonse!
アル　アルフォンス
なんで僕が逃げろって言ったときに
Why didn't you run away when
I told you to, you stupid brother!
逃げなかったんだよこのバカ兄
いや　だからアルを置いて逃げるわけには
Come on, I couldn't leave you behind and run away!
それがバカだって言うんだ
That's exactly why I'm calling you stupid!
What?! If I ran away, you might have been killed!
なんでだよ
オレだけ逃げたらお前殺されたかもしれないじゃんか
殺されなかったかもしれないだろ
I might have not been killed, too!
わざわざ死ぬ方を選ぶなんてバカのすることだ
Only an idiot would choose the path that leads to death!
兄貴に向かってあんまりバカバカ言うな
Quit calling your brother an idiot!
何度でも言ってやるさ
I'll say it as many times as I want!
生きて　生きて　生き延びて
If you'd lived, continued to live, and survived,
もっと錬金術を研究すれば
and continued to study alchemy,
元の体に戻る方法も
you could have found a way to get your limbs back
and maybe discovered how to save people like Nina!
ニーナみたいな子を救う方法も見つかるかもしれないのに
その可能性を捨てて死ぬ方を選ぶなんて
I wouldn't be able to forgive you if you chose to die by throwing all of those possibilities away!
そんなマネ絶対に許さない
ああっ　右手もげちゃったじゃないか
My arm came off! You stupid brother!
兄さんのバカたれ
あぁ　ボロボロだな　オレたち
We're really torn up, aren't we...
カッコ悪いったらありゃしねぇ
How uncool.
でも生きてる
But... we're alive.
うん　生きてる
Yeah. We sure are.
まったく万国スペシャル·ビックリショーだな　こりゃ
This seriously is a special all-around freak show, isn't it.
Sorry for keeping it from you.
あぁすまん
オーケー　上には内緒にしとくさ
No problem, I won't tell the higher-ups.
バレたら　いろいろ厄介なんだろ
It'll be somewhat troublesome if they find out, won't it?
ああ　兄はともかく
Yeah...
We can play off the part about Edward's limbs,
but we can't really make up an excuse for the younger one.
弟の体は言い逃れができんからな
それにしても　厄介なヤツに狙われたもんだ
But seriously... we've got quite the ugly customer coming after us.
イシュヴァールの民か
An Ishbalan, huh...
イシュヴァールの民は
Ishbalans were a tribe of people in the East
who worshipped Ishvala as their sole creator and God.
イシュヴァラを唯一絶対の創造神とする
東部の一部族だった
我が国に併合された後も　部分的に衝突はあったが
There were a few cases of feuds after we annexed the country,
１３年前
But thirteen years ago...
...when a military officer mistakenly shot and killed
an Ishbalan child, the situation devolved into a civil war.
軍将校が誤ってイシュヴァール人の子供を
射殺してしまった事件を機に
内乱へと発展した
暴動は暴動を呼び
A riot called forth more riots, and the civil war eventually spread throughout all of the east.
いつしか内乱は東部全域へと広がった
７年にも及ぶ攻防の末
The order given from the highest level of
our military after seven years of battle was...
軍上層部から下された命令は
イシュヴァー殲滅
...Ishbalan extermination.
多くの国家錬金術師が人間兵器として駆り出された
Many State Alchemists were roped in to act as human weapons.
そして国家錬金術師は　目覚ましい戦果をもたらした
And the State Alchemists brought forth remarkable achievements.
だから　イシュヴァールの生き残りである
That's why that man, who is a survivor of the Ishbalans, has a legitimate reason for wanting revenge.
あの男の復讐には正当性がある
くっだらねぇ
Bullshit!
There's no legitimacy in revenge that drags in people who have nothing to do with it!
関係ない人間を巻き込む復讐に
正当性もクソもあるかよ
All he's doing is sugar-coating an ugly spirit of vengeance by calling himself God's hand and pretending to be all noble!
醜い復讐心を　神の代行人ってオブラートに包んで
崇高ぶってるだけだ
だが牙をむき向かってくるのは事実だ
But the hard truth is he's hostile toward us.
そして我々も　死ぬわけにはいかない
And we can't die, either.
次に会ったときは問答無用で
The next time we see him, we'll crush him...
潰す
...without any questions asked.
はい
Yes, sir!
エド　アル
Ed, Al, what do you two plan on doing now?
お前たちはどうする　これから
また歩きだすよ
We're going to move forward again.
We can't come to a stop as long as we're alive, after all!
生きてるかぎり　立ち止まってられないからな
兄さん
Brother...
まずはお前の体を直すために
First off, I need to get my arm fixed in order to get your body back to normal.
オレの腕を元に戻さないと
鎧と魂の定着方法を知ってんのはオレだけだからな
Since I'm the only one who knows how to affix a soul to an armor.
だね
You're right about that!
しょうがねぇ
Guess we've got no choice.
久しぶりに行ってくるか
What do you say we go and visit our mechanic?
We haven't shown our faces there in a while.
うちの整備士のところに
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本语字幕录入：FAYFAY
戦いに傷ついた体を休めるべく
Winry's smile greets Ed and Al, who return
to Resembool to rest their battle-wounded bodies.
リゼンブールに帰ったエドたちを
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs
ウィンリィの笑顔が出迎える
一方　賢者の石は深い謎とともに
On the other hand, a philosopher's stone
appears before them, shrouded in a deep mystery.
エドたちの前に姿を現すのだった
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第六話　希望の道
Episode 6, The Road of Hope.
夕焼けの丘に吹く風は少年に何を運ぶのか
The wind blows through the hill in the sunset.
What does it bring the boy?